Allison Brown

Software Developer

Phone: 647 648 1893

Email: allison.brown@hotmail.com

I am a resourceful and creative software developer, that brings a unique blend of skills and experiences from my background in education and healthcare. My journey into web development was sparked by my role at the University of Toronto Scarborough (UTSC), where I began dabbling in coding to create engaging and effective learning resources for students. Since then, I have completed multiple courses and projects to expand my technical skills.

Projects & Links

Tents & Trails

A campground review site built with the MERN stack.

PuzzleSwap

A drag and drop puzzling utilizing Pragmatic Drag & Drop

Tv Tune Trivia

A TV trivia app built using Spotify's API

Portfolio

A showcase for my projects!

LinkedIn

GitHub

Technical Skills

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript

MERN

Git/GitHub

WCAG guidelines

Work Experience

Learning Skills Specialist

OCAD University

09/2023 - current

- Creating and managing digital learning content of LMS course (Canvas) for students on academic probation
- Developing and evaluating learning skills programming to assess efficacy and improve implementation
- Assessing student's learning skills and needs to develop individualized learning plans

Learning Strategist

University of Toronto (Scarborough)

09/2021 - 09/2023

- Collaborated with web developers to create digital learning content of LMS course (Canvas) for students with disabilities transitioning to university
- Created a <u>learning skills website</u> to provide self-serve resources for students with disabilities

Education

React Bootcamp

Udemy

12/2023 - 04/2024

JavaScript Course

Juno College

02/2023 - 04/2023

Web Developer Bootcamp

Udemy

01/2023 - 12/2023

Master of Kinesiology

University of Toronto

2017 - 2019

Accessibility Counsellor

York University

12/2019 - 09/2021

- Interpreted medical documentation to recommend accommodations and assistive technology for students with disabilities
- Mediating conflict and fostering positive relationships between stakeholders (i.e.: faculty, students, admin)

Program Coordinator

University of Toronto (St. George)

08/2019 - 04/2020

- Supervised and trained graduate kinesiology students on principles of motor learning and adaptive physical activity
- Developed and evaluated physical literacy program for children with disabilities

Registered Kinesiologist

Holland Bloorview Kids Rehabilitation Hospital

09/2016 - 08/2018

 Designed and implemented exercise programming to promote motor learning and improve gait patterns for children with CP

Registered Kinesiologist

Lifemark

08/2015 - 05/2017

 Prescribed exercises & performed functional capacity evaluations for patients recovering from illness and injury